다이간다는 방을 밝게 하고 적당히 떨어져서 봐!
Watch Daigunder in a bright room and keep some distance!
Смотри Дайгандера со включённым светом, сидя подальше от экрана!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
Дайгандер!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다다다다다다다다다!
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе,
마음의 눈을 열어라
Open your eyes of soul
Распахни шире око души
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
(Bakutou Sengen Daigunder)
Боевой претендент Дайгандер!
뜨거운 마음을 담아
With all your hot heart
Пусть меня охватит твой жар сердца,
오늘도 기적을 맹새해
I will make a miracle today too
Чтобы сотворить сумел я чудо
드래곤 소드 작렬이야
Dragon Sword bursts
Вспыхнет ярким светом Меч Дракона!
싸워야 할 라이벌은
The rival I have to fight against is
Побороть я должен свой упавший дух,
좌절하려는 내 자신
right here, dispirited myself
что пути к успеху преграждает мне,
어제보다도 진화해서
Evolve even more than yesterday
Вырасти сегодня больше, чем вчера
강해져라!
And become strong!
И сильнее стать!
다다다다 다 다 다 다다
Dadadada da da da dada
Дададада-да-да-да-дада!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
Пушка Дракона!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
불타라 불타올라라
Burn and flare up
Пыл борьбы разожги ты в себе
에너지 전개로
Open up all your energy and
Дай энергии выход, сказав...
다다다다다다 다
Dadadadadada da
Дададададада-да!!
다이 다이 다이 다이 다이간다
Dai Dai Dai Dai Daigunder
Дай-Дай-Дай-Дай-Дайгандер
쓰러트려라 타도해라
Defeat and knock down
Победи и врагов одолей
빛나는 강철의
Fighter of shining steel
Сталью сверкает тело твоё,
폭투선언 다이간다
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
제 21 화
The 21st Episode
Эпизод 21
자립선언!
Independence Declaration!
커맨더로의 길!!
The Road of Commander!!
(en: Fight or Get Off The Bot)
전설의 커맨더?
The legendary commander?
카사블랑코 시티의 팀 쿄조. 슈퍼 파워의 아폴로네우스하고 머큐리 X를 지시해서
Team Kyozo of Casa Blanco City. He instructed Apoloneuss and Mercury X of super powers,
수많은 배틀에서 승리한 전설의 커맨더.
and won in numerous battles. That's why he's the legendary commander.
래.
That's what they say.
그런 놈하고 배틀하는 거야? 대단해?
We're fighting against a team like that? Awesome!
좀이 쑤시네!
It's going to be exciting!
팀 아키라를 전세계에 알릴 찬스! 영화에, TV에, 옷에!
It's our chance to let the world know about Team Akira! You'll be on movies! On TV programs! On clothes!
계산이 안 돼! 큰 벌이가 될 게 틀림없어!
This is out of my calculation! This will make a big profit!
그래도 이 팀은 이미 은퇴하지 않았나. 그런 팀이 왜 트레이닝 배틀을 신청하나.
But didn't that team already retire? Why would such a team ask for a training battle?
보스가 말하는 대로야!
Boss is right!
그런 건 걱정하지 마!
Don't worry about that!
우리 소문을 듣고 배틀을 하고 싶어진 거야!
They simply became wanting to have a battle against us after hearing about us!
오늘 여기 남아 있을 애니멀 유닛을 위해서라도 힘내야지.
We have to do our best, for Animal Unit, staying here today, too.
그래, 그렇다.
Yes, you're right.
-그렇게 된 거라면!
-팍팍 배틀하자!
-Well if we're going to do so,
-then let's have an excellent battle!
늦어! 아직이냐! 대체 뭘 하고 있는 거야?
They're late! Aren't they here yet?
왔군!
They're here!
크다!
It's big!
대단해!
Awesome!
이만큼이나 우승했다면 영화에 TV에, 그리고 또... 역시 돈 잔뜩 벌겠어!
They've won this much! We're going on movies and TV programs! We're really are going to be rich!
멋져!
Cool!
잘 와 주셨다! 내가 전설의 커맨더, 히무로 쿄조다!
Welcome to my place! I am the legendary commander Himuro Kyozo!
나, 팀 아키라의 커맨더, 아케보노 아키라!
I am the commander of Team Akira, Akebono Akira!
나는 류구!
I'm Ryugu!
매니저 하루카에요.
I'm Haruka, the manager.
어?
Huh?
다들 건강하구나!
You all look good!
계속 숨어있지만 말고 인사해라!
Don't hide there; say hi to them!
손자 쿄이치다!
He's my grandson, Kyoichi!
-어이!
-잘 부탁해!
-Heya!
-Nice to meet ya!
잘 부탁해...
Nice to meet you...
사람들하고 떨어진 곳에서 나하고 둘이서만 살다 보니 내성적이 되어 버렸다.
He became introvert as he's living only with me, apart from people.
이해해 줘라!
Please understand!
그건 그래도, 대단한 수의 트로피구나.
Anyway, what a number of trophies you have.
오, 그렇냐? 그럼 하나 정도 가져가도 상관 없다!
Oh, is that so? Then you can take one or two!
아르케시티 토너먼트에서 우승했을 때의 트로피다.
It's a trophy I got when I won in Arkecity Tournament.
응, 응!
Yeah, yeah!
건네준 누나들이 내 취향이었지!
The girls who handed me that were my type!
뭐?
What?
이건 실타운 아블루블루 컵 때의 거다!
This is from Siltown Ablublue Cup!
옆에 있던 누나들이 또 내 취향!
Girls at there were my type again!
오, 이 대회 담당인 누나들도 예뻤지.
Oh, the girl managers for that competition were pretty, too.
어, 그리고...
And then...
저, 트레이닝 배틀 말인데요.
About the training battle...
어? 아, 그렇지! 하마터면 잊어먹을 뻔했구나.
Oh? Ah, I get it! I almost forgot.
배틀은 두 번으로 첫 번째는 하이브리드 매치, 두 번째는 싱글 매치 어떠냐?
There will be two battles. The first one will be hybrid match, and the second is single match. Does that work?
-OK!
-응!
-Great!
알겠냐, 쿄이치?
Got it, Kyoichi?
어?
What?
알겠냐니, 대전하는 게...
So we're fighting him?
쿄이치! 평소의 기개 맘껏 발휘해라!
Kyoichi! Show your usual spirit as much as you can!
우효횻이라니 저 할배하고 배틀하는 거 아니었어?
What, we weren't fighting that old man?
왠지 바람 빠져...
How disappointing...
팀 쿄이치. 배틀 로봇은 스나이프스 피셔하고 스나이프스 킹.
Team Kyoichi. His battle robots are Snipes Fisher and Snipes King.
그라인더 타입의 푸트워크에 뛰어나고, 근거리에서의 머신 건 공격, 원거리에서의 미사일 공격도 특기야.
They are Grinder Type. They are good at footwork, and they're good at machine gun attacks
at close range, and missile attacks at long range.
전형적인 히트 앤 어웨이 타입이네.
They're the usual Hit-and-Away type.
히트 앤 어웨이?
Hit and away?
그러니까 말야, 이 타입은 치고 빠지고, 빠졌다 생각하면 다시 치러 온다는 거야.
It means that they will hit and run away immediately, and when you think they're far away, they'll come and hit again.
그러니까 적이 잘 공격하지 못한다는 거야.
Following that is they can't attack so well.
나비처럼 날고 벌처럼 쏜다. 우미한 전법.
Float like a butterfly, sting like a bee. It's an elegant strategy.
아니야! 힘이 없는 거야! 잡아서 못 움직이게 하면 끝장난다는 거야!
Nope! They're simply powerless! If you get them and stop them from moving, they're all yours!
-OK!
-알겠다!
-Understood.
불타는 용기사 류구!
Burning Dragon Warrior Ryugu!
파이터 체인지!
Fighter Change!
쥬라식 솔저 본렉스!
Jurassic Soldier Bonerex!
커맨드 데커, 가드.
Command Decker, guard.
히트포인트 체크.
Hitpoint check.
준비...
Ready...
배틀 로봇 파이트!
Battle robots, fight!
가라!
Go!
가, 가 봐, 킹, 피셔!
G- go, King, Fisher!
류구! 나이트 슬래시야!
Ryugu! Use Knight Slash!
OK! 나이트 슬래시!
OK! Knight Slash!
제일 첫 공격은, 어디... 락 크래시!
The first attack will be, err... Rock Crash!
아, 아니야!
N- no!
핑거 머신 건...이 아니라, 팔꿈치 벌컨... 도 아니라...
Finger Machine Gun... no, it isn't that... Elbow Vulcan...'s wrong...
뭐야?
What's wrong with him?
아, 그래! 갓츠 해머야!
R- right! Guts Hammer!
어이!
Hey!
저런!
No!
설마 저거 작전?
Is that some kind of strategy?
-히트 앤 어웨이 따위 하게 두지 마!
-그래!
-Don't let them do hit and away!
-Right!
킹, 거기서... 어째... 할아버지라면 이럴 때...
King, you'll do... what? I wonder what would my grandpa did in times like this...
어이! 뒤로 돌아 들어가서 백 드롭이다!
Hey! Go round and cut in to back, and do Back Drop!
킹, 뒤로 돌아 들어가!
King, go round to back!
또 나쁜 습관이 나와 버렸구나!
Your bad habits are there again!
뭐야?
What's wrong?
모른다.
I don't know.
안 돼, 상대의 연극에 넘어가면. 분명 작전이니까.
Don't fall over to them. It's must be a strategy!
배틀 로봇 변환.
Battle robots, conversion.
트라이혼! 데스펙터! 건더! 배틀 인!
Trihorn! Despector! Gunder! Battle In!
파이터 체인지!
Fighter Change!
사신귀족 데스펙터!
Noble Reaper Despector!
그리고 괴력의 문지기 트라이혼!
And Superstrength Gatekeeper, Trihorn!
류구! 건더! 헤드합체!
Ryugu! Gunder! Head Fusion!
폭투왕 다이간다!
Wild Fight King Daigunder!
쿄이치! 이건 네 자신과의 싸움이다! 온 마음을 다해 뭐든 해라!
Kyoichi! It's a fight against yourself! Do whatever to take your way through!
으, 응...
Y- yeah...
나이트호크 1호, 2호, 스카이호크, 배틀 인!
Nighthawk #1, #2, and Skyhawk! Battle In!
고베 킹!
Gobe King!
그거다! 위에서 공격해라! 가라!
That's it! Attack from upward! Go!
킹, 상승해!
King, go up!
어디, 이 다음엔... 어째...
Next, you'll... I don't know...
지금이야! 트라이혼, 데스펙터! 무장합체!
Now! Trihorn, Despector! Arming Fusion!
슬래시 커터!
Slash Cutter!
혼 스팅어!
Horn Stinger!
스나이프스 킹, 다운!
Snipes King, down!
쿄이치! 진짜는 지금부터다! 쿄이치!
Kyoichi! The real one begins now! Kyoichi!
할아버지... 나, 이제 못 해!
Grandpa... I can't do this anymore!
뭔 소리냐! 기죽으면 안 된다! 너는 내 손자다! 쓸데없는 소리 할 필요 없다!
What are you saying? You can do it! You're my grandson! No need for that!
쿄이치!
Kyoichi!
안 된다면 안 되는 거야!
If I said I can't, then I can't!
쿄이치!
Kyoichi!
팀 쿄이치, 기권! 승자, 팀 아키라!
Team Kyoichi, give up! Winner, Team Akira!
쿄이치...
Kyoichi...
어떻게 된 거야?
What's going on?
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
폭투선언 다이간다
Bakutou Sengen Daigunder
Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder
Боевой претендент Дайгандер
by Subdivers
Russian TL by SutoKuroi
Subdivers 번역
오늘은 미안했다.
I apologize for what happened today.
내일 한 번 더 있는 승부도 받아 줘라.
Please face him again in tomorrow's match.
그건 괜찮은데...
That's fine, but...
킹, 아팠지?
King, it must've been hurt.
내 힘이 부족해서 미안해.
I'm sorry, for not being good enough.
피셔도 미안해.
I'm sorry to you too, Fisher.
저기!
Hey!
-저녁 같이 먹자!
-다들 기다리고 있어!
-Let's eat dinner together!
-Everyone's waiting!
야, 같이 먹자!
Hey, let's eat together!
뭔 소리라도 좀 해 봐!
Say something!
나, 나를 안 될 놈이라 생각하고 있지?
I know what you're thinking about me.
-어?
-알고 있어. 다들 그렇게 생각한다는 건.
-What?
-I already know that everyone's thinking that.
히무로 쿄조의 손자니까 다들 내가 어떤 배틀을 하는지 보려고 싸우니까.
Since I'm the grandson of Himuro Kyozo, everyone comes to fight me to see how I fight.
그래도 이제 알겠어!
But I know now!
난 뭘 해도 안 돼.
Whatever I do, I won't make it.
뭐야, 저게!
What's wrong with him?
저 얘, 이해해 줘라.
Please understand him.
할아버지!
Grandpa!
저 얘가 배틀을 하고 싶다고 했을 때는 정말 기뻤다.
When that kid said that he wanted to do battles, I was really happy.
하늘에도 오를 듯 했다. 그렇지만 어느새 저렇게 되 버렸다.
I was on cloud nine. But at some point, he became like that.
저 얘는 자기가 할 수 있는 최대한 노력하고 있다는 것만은 안다.
I know that kid is trying his best.
나는... 나는 단지 쿄이치가 쭉쭉 싸우기를 바랄 뿐이다.
I just want Kyoichi to fight freely at his will.
아니, 내가 잘못 생각한 것일지도 모르지. 말이 전부가 아니니까.
Maybe I was wrong. Word isn't all.
나는 쿄이치를 좀 제멋대로 키운 듯 하구나.
It seems that I spoiled Kyoichi.
저도 할아버지 있어요! 지금 어디서 뭘 하는지는 모르지만!
I have a grandfather, too! Even though I don't know what's he doing at where.
자기가 원하는 것만 골라 하고, 우린 마음대로 내버려 둬요!
He only does whatever he wants, and leave us do whatever we want!
그래도 언제나 어디선가 봐 주고 있어요!
But still, he's watching us from somewhere all the time!
하지메 박사냐?
Is it Prof. Hajime?
알고 있어요? 제 할아버지.
Did you know my grandpa?
배틀 로봇 공학의 일인자 하지메 박사를 모른다는 건 불가능하다. 그렇군. 냅두었는데도 강하게 자랐구나.
Everybody knows about Prof. Hajime, when he's the leading expert of battle robot engineering.
그런 소릴 해 주시고!
Thank you!
내일은 봐주지 말고 단단히 해 줘라! 그 얘가 만약 다시는 하고 싶지 않다고 해도 난 상관 없다!
Don't go easy on him tomorrow! If he says that he never wants to do that again, then let it be so!
배틀 로봇, 파이트!
Battle robots, fight!
-류구! 봐주지 마!
-당연!
-Ryugu, don't go easy on him!
-Of course!
왜 그래! 배틀은 이미 시작됐어!
What's wrong? The battle has already begun!
할아버지...
Grandpa...
-류구! 연속 공격해!
-OK!
-Ryugu! Keep attacking!
할아버지...
Grandpa...
피셔...
Fisher...
도와줘, 할아버지.
Help me, grandpa.
뭐가 문제야! 왜 할아버지한테 의지하려 하는 거야?
What's wrong with you? Why do you keep trying to depend on your grandfather?
할아버지가 설마 전설의 커맨더라고 해도 필드에 선 이상 아무도 안 도와줘!
Whether you're grandfather is a legendary commander, nobody will help you when you're on the field!
도와줘!
Help me!
류구! 나이트 슬래시야!
Ryugu! Use Knight Slash!
나이트 슬래시!
Knight Slash!
피셔!
Fisher!
쿄이치 바보! 왜 달아나는 거야? 왜 도망치고 마는 거야?
Kyoichi, you idiot! Why are you running away? Why do you end up retreating?
아무도 널 안 될 놈이라고는 생각하지 않아! 네가 멋대로 그렇게 생각하고 있을 뿐이야!
Nobody thinks that you won't make anything! It's only you who's thinking so on your own!
-다들 그렇게 생각해.
-그렇게 생각 안 해!
-Everyone thinks so.
-Nobody does!
그렇게 생각해. 할아버지도 안 될 손자라 생각해.
Everyone does. My grandpa thinks me of a spoiled grandson.
아니야! 네 할아버지는 그런-
No! Your grandfather never-
아니야? 나 들었어. 어제 할아버지 그렇게 말했잖아.
It isn't? I heard that grandpa saying so last night.
내가 배틀을 하고 싶지 않다고 해도 더는 상관 안 쓴다고...
He won't mind even if I say I don't want to do this anymore.
그건 역시 난 안 될 테니까 포기하라는 거지? 그렇지?
That must be meaning that I should give up because I won't make it. Isn't it right?
맞다.
You're right.
너는 안 될 놈이다! 전설의 커맨더 히무로 쿄조의 손자가 아니다! 이 승부는 버려라!
You won't make it! You're not the grandson of the legendary commander Himuro Kyozo! Give up that battle!
어서 기권해라!
Resign the battle!
할아버지...
Grandpa...
안 해.
I won't.
기권 따위...
I won't...
give up!
안 해!
I won't give up!
쿄이치!
Kyoichi!
스나이프스 피셔, 가라!
Snipes Fisher, go!
방심하지 마, 류구!
Don't let your guards down, Ryugu!
일어나라! 승리를 노려라! 뜨거워지는 고상한 열정
Stand up! Aim for the victory! The sublime passion is heating up
Встань и борись! К победе стремись! Горячая страсть нам сердца раскаляет!
물론!
Of course!
와라!
Face me!
록 크래시야!
Do Rock Crash!
얼마이고 상처나도 진정한 강함을 알 때까지
No matter how it hurts, until we grasp the true strength
Пусть раны болят, не заметим того, и силы в себе, невиданные, откроем мы!
류구! 그대로 나이트 퀘이크야!
Ryugu! Do Knight Quake like that!
나이트 퀘이크!
Knight Quake!
핑거 머신 건!
Finger Machine Gun!
바람을 갈라라! 가슴을 펴라! 쏜살같이
Cut the wind! Straight yourself up! At full speed
Ветер разрежь ударом! Выпрями грудь свою! Помчись вперёд
류구!
Ryugu!
숨이 멎는 배틀, 피말리는 순간이 나를 불러
Breathtaking battle! The moment on the edge is calling me
Голову битва вскружит! Держимся на краю! Азарта миг с собой вдруг позовёт
배틀 로봇 변환.
Battle robots, conversion.
나이트호크 1호, 2호, 배틀 인!
Nighthawk #1 and #2, Battle In!
우리도 가자! 건더, 배틀 인!
Let's do this too! Gunder, Battle In!
다가가라! 간격을 좁혀라! 흥망을 결판내라
Sidle up! Lessen the distance! Settle the rise and fall
Ещё шаг вперёд! Сократи расстояние! Упав, поднимись без сомнений вновь!
얼빠진 짓만 하고 있을 수는 없어 쓰려진다면 몇번이라도
No blunders anymore. No matter the number defeated,
Промашек мы больше с тобой не допустим, неважно, как много нас ждёт врагов.
좋아, 피셔! 팔 이탈!
Good, Fisher! Eject your arm!
류구! 건더! 헤드합체!
Ryugu! Gunder! Head Fusion!
일어나라! 승리를 노려라! 뜨거워지는 고상한 열정
Stand up! Aim for the victory! The sublime passion is heating up
Встань и борись! К победе стремись! Горячая страсть нам сердца раскаляет!
얼마이고 상처나도 진정한 강함을 알고 싶어
No matter how it hurts, we want to grasp the true strength
Пусть раны болят, не заметим того, и силы найдём, невиданные
폭투왕 다이간다!
Wild Fight King Daigunder!
눈부신 반짝임 속에서 환호로 끓는 콜로세움
The Colosseum is boiling in cheer inside a dazzling glitter
Шумят голоса на трибунах арен, и в ярких огнях Колизей утопает
지금이야!
Now!
핑거 머신 건!
Finger Machine Gun!
호크 샷!
Hawk Shot!
팔꿈치 벌컨 발사!
Elbow Vulcan, fire!
언젠가는 대답이 나오면 오로지 자기 자신을 믿어
When the answer comes out, we believe in nothing but ourselves
И вновь прозвучит наш главный ответ: мы верим в себя, и нет никого, кто сломит нас!
트라이앵글 스나이퍼즈 샷!
Triangle Snipers Shot!
다이간다!
Daigunder!
쿄이치!
Kyoichi!
히트포인트가!
Look at the Hitpoints!
탄환이 없어지는 게 먼저냐, 우리 히트포인트가 없어지는게 먼저냐 승부다!
We'll see what disappears first - your ammo or our Hitpoints!
기대해 줘! 힘을 줘! 친구들이여
Put your hopes on us! Give us the power! Dear friends
Искренне в нас поверьте! Новых придайте сил! Друзья мои
그래, 나뿐만이 아니야 다 그런 거 아니겠어? 언제라도 최선을 다하고 싶어
Yes, not only me, but everyone feels the same! I want to do my best
Это не только я, ведь... все чувствуют то, что я? Стремлюсь всегда к тому, чтоб лучше быть
그래! 잘한다, 쿄이치! 눈앞이다! 힘내라!
Yes! You're doing great, Kyoichi! You're almost there! Keep it up!
응!
Yeah!
문득 스쳐가는 방황 따위는 추호도 없는 듯이
Pretend the suddenly crossing hesitation like nothing at all
И если на сердце сомнения лягут, легко ты смахни их без лишних слов
한순간의 틈을 잡아 다그치는 때는 지금
Catch the gap of a moment! Time to press answers is right now
Поймать блик момента важнее станет! Ответы получить будь на всё готов
다이간다! 클러스터 파워 전개야!
Daigunder! Activate Cluster Power!
맞서라! 승리를 노려라! 상처투성이 흥분하는 감격!
Fight against! Aim for the victory! Wounded emotion is proud
Упрямо борись! К победе стремись! Затянутся шрамы под градом эмоций!
피셔, 전력으로 가! 마이크로 미사일 발사!
Fisher, go at full force! Fire Micro Missiles!
얼마이고 상처나도 진정한 강함을 알고 싶어
No matter how it hurts, we want to grasp the true strength
Пусть раны болят, не заметим того, и силы найдём, невиданные
다이간다! 드래곤 캐논!
Daigunder! Use Dragon Cannon!
드래곤 캐논!
Dragon Cannon!
공격!
Attack!
눈부신 반짝임 속에서 환호로 끓는 콜로세움
The Colosseum is boiling in cheer inside a dazzling glitter
Шумят голоса на трибунах арен, и в ярких огнях Колизей утопает
언젠가는 대답이 나오면 오로지 자기 자신을 믿어
When the answer comes out, we believe in nothing but ourselves
И вновь прозвучит наш главный ответ: мы верим в себя, и нет никого, кто сломит нас!
히트포인트 제로. 스나이프스 피셔, 다운. 승자, 팀 아키라!
Hitpoints, zero. Snipes Finsher, down. Winner, Team Akira!
해냈어!
We did it!
피셔!
Fisher!
잘 했어! 잘 해 줬어!
You've done great! Thank you!
너도 힘냈다!
You've done great, too!
쿄이치! 훌륭했다!
Kyoichi! That was excellent!
잘 힘냈다!
You've done your best!
아키라 군, 대단한 배틀 고마워!
Akira, thank you for the excellent battle!
나야말로! 조마조마했어!
Me too! That was a close fight!
다음은 나도 상대해 주겠다! 좋냐?
I'll fight you next time! Will that make up?
-네, 물론! 그치?
-어!
-Yeah, of course! Agree?
-Yeah!
가자!
Let's go!
-그럼!
-바이바이!
-Then
-bye-bye!
-어서 와!
-기다려!
-Hurry up!
-Wait for us!
다음은... 다음은 꼭 이겨 보일게, 할아버지!
I'll... I'll defeat them next time no matter what, grandpa!
그래! 그 기세다!
Great! That's the spirit!
우리 할아버지 지금 뭐 하고 있을까?
I wonder what is my grandpa doing now.
어?
Huh?
왜 그래?
What's wrong?
응? 아, 아니야, 아무것도.
Huh? Oh, it's nothing!
그럼 다들 다이랜드에 돌아가자!
Then let's go back to Dailand, everyone!
끝없는 꿈을 꾸고 있어
Dreaming an endless dream
Я сон бесконечный вижу опять перед собой
몇번이고 쓰러져도
I fall down over and over again
Как упал, и лечу вниз вновь и вновь.
저 구름 위에는 분명히
Up over those clouds
Там, где-то в высотах, за чертой облаков
푸른 하늘이 펼쳐져 있을 거야
a blue sky awaits
голубое небо ждёт меня!
강해지기 위해서라면 누구도 혼자서는
To be strong, nobody can ever become
Сильным быть, чтоб никто превзойти не смог
강해지고 뜨거워질 수 없어
strong and hot, by oneself
Стать сильней, горячей, сам я хочу!
불꽃의 Fight Fight Fighting soul
Flaming fightin' fightin' fighting soul
Так гори, душа, душа бойца!
용기를 마주치는 그 때
When you face your courage
Смелость повстречай, и пусть ведёт она тебя в жизни.
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
느껴져 바로 너라는 게
I can feel it, yes, it's you
Я это чувствую, да, это ты!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
다
녀
왔
어!
H
o
m
e!
Д
о
м
а!
둘은 서로의 영웅
The two are heroes of each other
Два героя - части одного, нерушимы связи,
질 수 없는 같은 내일을
They run towards to the same tomorrow
Вместе в новый день по одной тропе спешат
바라보고 달려
that they cannot lose
И не собьются с неё!
배틀 로봇 팬 모임에 불려진 우리.
We've been called to battle robot fans' meeting.
그래도 그 와중, 류구가 배틀 로봇 유괴범들에게 납치되어 버렸어!
But during that, Ryugu has been taken by battle robot kidnapper!
놈들의 아지트에 몰래 들어간 나는 류구를 데리고 달아났어!
I sneaked into their hideout and ran out with Ryugu!
근데 류구는 기억을 삭제당해서 날 잊어버렸어!
But Ryugu's memories have been deleted and he forgot about me!
류구! 우리 뜨거운 우정을 기억해내 줘!
Ryugu! Remember our burning friendship!
폭투선언 다이간다의 다음 이야기!
망각선언! 잃어버린 기억!!
Next time on Wild Fight Declaration Daigunder!
Oblivion Declaration! Lost Memories!!